Playing for Time is a drama, music, history film directed by Daniel Mann.
When a Jewish songstress is plucked from the stage and sent to Auschwitz, she and other musicians find themselves assigned to
a terrible task—using their talents to soothe fellow prisoners who are sentenced to die in the gas chambers.
Fania Fenelon, played by Vanessa Redgrave.
Alma Rose, played by Jane Alexander.
Mala, played by Maud Adams.
Olga, played by Christine Baranski.
Etalina, played by Robin Bartlett.
Elzvieta, played by Marisa Berenson.
Playing for Time is a 1980 CBS television film, written by Arthur Miller and based on
musician Fania Fénelon's autobiography The Musicians of Auschwitz.
Vanessa Redgrave stars as Fénelon.
Playing for Time was based on Fénelon's experience as a female prisoner in the Auschwitz concentration camp, where
she and a group of classical musicians were spared in return for performing music for their captors.
The film was later adapted as a play by Miller.
This was the last film of director Daniel Mann.
Parts of the film were directed by Joseph Sargent, but
only Mann was credited as director.
The film explores themes of concentration camp, world war ii, auschwitz-birkenau
concentration camp, orchestra, based on memoir or autobiography.
The tone is emotional.